Breakfast Club morning everybody is DJ
envy Angela Guiche Alamein the guy we
are the breakfast club we got a special
guest in the building family in the
building
Amanda sales is back seals no threesomes
[Laughter]
no but someone asked me to be in like a
polygynous relationship right I want you
and so-and-so the two angels I've been
sent to one day being my children okay
he's my boyfriend in college and we said
it's like this like a legit and then we
had to go to class like right after we
got a girl was she cool
no with some chick they didn't even go
to the school but he had decided that
like you know and I and me being the
type of person like who will try to just
ask for more info like just to see how
crazy this is gonna get it was like so
how would this work is there gonna be a
schedule and he was like yeah like you
have Mondays and Tuesdays you have
although you really playing this out and
you snuffed him and that says a lot
because Angela I mean man did somebody
that will tell you down with intellect
yeah because you know what he had my
like he had at like we had broken up and
then he came back and was like I just
want to be with you like you have
haven't been the same without you you
know all this stuff and then we're
hugging he was like but can you beacon a
man be in love with two women like you
thought about enough for somebody who's
loved him I thought about that she was
like you know what this got to go
physically she cracked the neck
I am I really don't be on that I mean
you know what I
I feel like it's always in me cuz I just
have rage you know I'm saying like I
think especially if you're a conscious
person you have rage late bowling-ball
was there he said to be conscious and so
it lives close to the surface and so I
try to refine the rage at all times but
sometimes you know you just the emotions
get a little too much that's why I'm
always like you know I it's important
for me to always be a communicator
right and just be really good at
communicating because if it goes to
blows I really feel like a Hanna myself
that's good I mean I've been in one
fight and I pulled out our weave I'm
just curious have been a long time ago
this fight took place approximately ten
years ago in front of soup and burger on
West days but the thing is I tell you
let me tell you what how is how the
self-destruction happens the situation
was that an acquaintance of a friend of
mine was like oh I heard you were used
to date so-and-so and I say yeah she was
like oh my sister is with him and I was
like tell her be careful he'd be lying
about his baby mom account and she's
like what you mean and I was like he had
one and now I heard he had three and
that's when we broke up okay and so I
was like just you know the tally is on
okay and so that's forward I was at
Subin burger and then the same
acquaintances came in with a homegirl
and she was like oh I told my friend
about what you said and she told homeboy
and yada yada yada and I was like well
why would she tell him that it's like
that's that's what I'm trying to put all
I was trying to put her on and so then I
was like that wasn't smart of her like
that was actually kind of corny like so
they left then the person I'm with is
like yo
the two girls that were here want you to
come outside now remember I don't think
that way so I'm like yeah I think
conversation like we're done eating not
like meet me outside and so I was like
okay and she was like and this is a good
time to tell you that the friend that
was with her is actually the sister that
she was talking about you were they set
me up
really I come outside she comes up to me
and she's like we need to talk
woman-to-woman and I'm just like I what
are we discussing like what is the
conversation and she was like well you
know you need to keep my man's name at
your mouth and I was like but I was
trying to help look out for you right
girls I'll be when to hear stuff about
their boyfriend like mm maybe and so
anyway she put her hand in my face and I
literally calmly removed pushed away
because I touched her hand that I had
opened the door so then she was like
back and she snuck me if she stole on me
and then I was like and I am what's
Indian so like you know I do have an
extra level of rage that it's like we
have turbo rage and that kicks in so the
Nutmeg rage came in and then and then it
just was on now here's the funny to do a
flip there were like eleven chicks that
were in the that were in the restaurant
yes yes and they were all lesbians they
were all friends they were all lesbians
they run outside and break the fight up
and then like whisk her off into a car
and I'm saying they're like and then
they pull out cocoa butter from they
purse butter on my eye because she tried
to pull out my eye on and her hair is on
the ground he taped this and then they
were like please just tell us this isn't
over a [ __ ] head and I was like you
know what it's over and it was like it
was like do the right thing they were
all like
but homeboy ends up dumping her and told
her no one puts hands on Amanda that's a
rat I don't know but at the end of the
day was like was it worth it no it
wasn't worth it it's never worth it it's
missing situations like that when you're
just a woman trying to inform another
woman but you know what when you do that
women always go back and tell the guy
well this person said this that oh yeah
you got mad baby bubbles when you hear
that from Amanda yeah that always
happened and he still was like I certain
people you know how you can't tell stuff
to certain people about their man
because you know they're gonna go right
back with that man said this anyway
sometimes you like look you already know
what it is so enjoy yourself yeah I
can't be mad at that though they gotta
expect it you got expected a few dated a
girl and then that girl knows another
woman and that woman may say something
bad about you you know guys know the
whole facts may be brainwashed did you
see the woman gets mad at you and out of
her man and you're like why are you mad
at me I'm just trying to put you on my
so how did I be knowing your HBO special
change your life you know you made me
cry last time you kept me before the
special right yeah no special we didn't
tell you after the dopes amazing no
thank you and the screening of it which
was amazing everybody loved it was like
sitting in the audience with everybody
it was like a reunion or something was
everybody's talking to the screen crazy
and then Amanda came out and it was just
that everything went crazy in there that
night it was really nice you be in the
audience and hear what people were
saying about it as they were watching
and especially women I think there were
so many things as a woman you can relate
to because it was like funny but it was
also just really conversational I mean
yeah I liked that I really I've had such
an incredible response from it like to
this day it's just been interesting to
see like what people take away from it
and like I always wanted to be an emcee
and have people quote my raps and so
it's interesting
like that didn't happen but people are
quoting my special and it's like oh I
guess that's the same thing so now you
got a rap from the special now I got a
whole we won't play that this morning no
but I just I just didn't I really was
honestly very excited about how how
people have been so able to see
themselves in the special that's the
thing that you were talking about like
just a lot of women have been like thank
you for giving me a voice like thank you
for creating a space someone wrote
something the other day on my Instagram
where they said I didn't sometimes I
don't realize I'm holding my breath
until I'm in a space where I can breathe
again thank you for creating that space
Wow
and I was just like damn like you just
because you're just you think sometimes
like okay I like this but no one else is
like gonna necessarily like this and I
feel like I've been working in a
different space where I Instagram it
kind of taken over as like my thing and
it was very important for me to pull the
reins back and like let people know like
no I'm that was something that happened
or if the humbug but I'm artists why
have an important for you to first and
foremost create those spaces for black
one because you said that at the
beginning it especially said this is for
my sisters we just don't have those
spaces and nobody's thinking about us
nobody was even thinking to make those
spaces so if we don't think about it it
just won't happen you know it's very
frustrating to be a specific kind of
black woman to like to be independent
and to be educated and to be adamant and
intense and serious like I think a lot
of us who've had to who have excelled in
our business or in education have had to
be those things and those things
oftentimes get misconstrued into the
whole angry black women trope or into
the whole you don't have to be by
yourself you ain't you ain't gonna be
able to get no man trope etc etc and so
it's just if we're not creating spaces
to normalize that like no we have all
those things that we also have emotions
we're also vulnerable we also don't want
to have our superwoman cape on all the
time we also don't want to have to be
strong black women like that's not the
thing that we're like striving to be
it's something we had to be just by
nature of condition
and not wanting to get you know bowled
over and we'd be saving the world like
every day so it's nice to have spaces
where we can talk about like okay I
saved the world but also my toes are
done and that was important you know
interesting about that that's one of the
reasons I actually started going it
there so cuz I don't want to put so much
load on my wife but it's like we just
think the strongest people in our lives
are black women because of our mothers
because of our grandma we are the strong
yes yes butch I don't always have to be
strong sometimes we gotta leave space
for y'all to be vulnerable just like you
got to leave space for men to be
vulnerable
absolutely and sometimes it just feels
like our role has become the bearer of
everyone's burden because we're so good
at it and we do it with style we keep
our edges laid in the midst of it so
it's a being like damn they look so good
doing it it must be so easy like let me
power on some more and it's like you and
the other part of this it will be
gracious about it like so many black
women like myself we are like please
give me give me your burden so I can
help you be better you know we want to
be there for brothers in such a very
very real way and so sometimes it just
can get a little out of hand because
then we forget to be there for ourselves
and you know you got to do both and you
want to have other people like giving
you the space to remind you that like
you can do both yeah I heard Debbie dad
say the other day that black women get
so much put on them that sometimes she
doesn't even realize that she really
isn't paint does this really hurt
because you're so accustomed to like
yeah like I mean I do this I do this you
know you have to self check on a regular
basis emotionally mentally physically
you have to sell check and sometimes you
know you self checking you're like okay
I'm good but sometimes you're like
and then you have to figure out like how
are you gonna reassess and so with the
comedy it's definitely important to me
to create a space where like you can
actually get a respite from all of the
reassessing and all of the overthinking
and all of the managing and just laugh
and laugh at the shared experiences that
we have how did especially change your
lifestyle that level up in like I always
say it's like there's it's you know it's
not overnight success it's overnight
opportunity like you're not an overnight
success because like you had to get you
had to be a certain level of successful
to get to that point right and even when
you get there it's like okay I have some
money now cool but the real change isn't
that the real change to me is more so
opportunity because and not about that
you're getting opportunities now
overnight you have become someone else's
opportunity and that's where [ __ ]
changes because now people are looking
at you as a currency for their own yes I
can get Amanda to host this show I star
in this show yes I can use Amanda's name
to clickbait to tell lies about her you
know to get my [ __ ] poppin I can use I
can use a minutes in this film to maybe
make it sound like there's positives and
negatives yeah I'm saying so but that is
the thing that I was not cognizant of
and I don't think I could well I don't
think in the real way you can't really
know it until you're in it happens yeah
also so what was it like for you the day
that it came on when it debut when
people were watching it were you looking
on your timeline to see what people were
saying or did you not care about that
cuz I know that's hard that's a hard
thing to do but where were you when
everybody was watching you and what we
we had a screening in LA with like my
family I lay with my mom was there and
my friends like it was really actually
like a very warm room and I actually had
a lot of people from New York that were
out there so I wasn't looking I wasn't
looking but what was cool was like
people hitting me you know and to this
day like people just will hit me you
know like I've definitely like literally
this week I had two different like
people I've known for a while like hit
me out the blue like I watched your
special and people that I did not expect
to hear from and we're like I watched
your special on the plane and you know
this is this is great and
thank you for doing this and someone
said they were like you're gonna be good
at this for a long time but that's a
hard thing to pull off though like all
that great material it's a whole
people's attention for that long a
period of time it goes fast it really
does like I'm I could do it good I could
do another special today not good at
dregs well there's that right I've been
on the road for the last six months I've
met all over this nation and I've been
able to I mean I retired that hour so I
don't do any of those jokes or all new
material all new material getting ready
for the next special yeah yeah it's a
hard to create another hour no I have
another hour I have a hour and a half
right now so when you're doing this
again you know the special I mean you
know the thing about it is like you
don't want to rush but then you don't
want to lose the theme correct but you
also need the right deal and I think
there were people that were definitely
kind of sleeping on me just because for
a reasons outside of myself but also
just the realities of like the market
and I really feel like I did a great job
of demonstrating I do something
different I'm you know um got my own
voice and that I have a strong base of
following that really does support what
I do when I do it so give me money do it
again I'll see you back on so for us
more funny in black yes you can be
actually in New York on the 16th and
17th 16th and 17 if we sell out those
shows we will add another one some are
funny in black though at the end of the
day like all this other stuff that I'm
doing smart funny and black is still at
the core of what I'm about because
especially in the time that we are in
this country it's still like a safe
space for black folks that just doesn't
exist we just did Kennedy Center we did
the biggest room at the Kingston we did
the concert halls 2,300 people I had the
Kennedy Center doing the I had folks in
the case they were doing the electric
slide I have folks in the case that a
swag surfing beautiful like it was
really just it was this this massive
amount of people all sharing the same
energy of we black we beautiful we're
celebrating this we're about it and it
was like I mean I said on stage I was
like damn it's the feds wasn't watching
me before they watched me now we in here
having too much fun and smart funny and
black does that for folks that don't
like we get to go to different
cities this time that we feel like don't
necessarily get that happening all the
time like Richmond Virginia and
Indianapolis and Kansas City and st.
Louis but then we also are going to
Atlanta and New York and Philly and
Houston and Dallas and Detroit and so we
just we're building this world where
it's a smart funny and black game show
that has live music we have two guests
that compete in games that I write and
create about that culture like history
in the black experience but outside of
that it's really just a big ole black
space of laughter and of intellect and
we need as many of those spaces as
possible what about white people
infiltrating space because they seen
your special on HP like I want to go see
her
I really appreciate people's support but
as much as the space is welcome to
everybody it is curated for the black
experience a for you white people and
it's fine you know what I always say at
the show like if you come to the show
and you are not a representative of the
black community like you're welcome but
know your place like I'm not going to
I'm not going to Bar Mitzvah is asking
when we gonna trash our slide like
when's that happening I'm not going to
you know expect that when I go to
certain cultural spaces so don't expect
us to tailor to your white chairs jewel
buttons when you had them on on you
Jesus came on the show with Joe button
when we were in New York and I always
tell folks don't drink before you do
smart funny in black because drinking
gives you liquid courage but it does not
give you liquid intellect and so it so
what happens is people come onstage
and at the end of the day the show is
smart funny and black and my audience is
smart funny in black so they're not just
gonna laugh or anything right so if you
start telling jokes that are beneath
them they will just be silent they're
just not interested so I think Jesus got
frustrated with the fact that he had
drank so much so he'd no longer had a
meter for his funny because I mean these
is a funny dude but the drinking is more
yeah
and they liquor clouds that and so he
wasn't getting the jokes off and he was
feeling away and then he started just
doing light-skinned jokes and like at a
certain point you're just like you know
I mean it's not you hit you hit that
punchline they ain't really rockin with
it no more and now you know me you call
me
the BART Street bully because you on my
stage and now you getting disrespectful
like you you making fun of the audience
you clown in the audience like a woman
came on stage he was being really kind
of overzealous and you got some broad
bringing you drinks to the stage even
though I've already asked you to stop
drinking and so then he just felt some
type of way and he left the show in the
middle of the show
and no one has ever done anything like
that it was very disrespectful he still
has not said anything to me about it to
clear it up and I expect an apology
because at the end of the day like I'm
creating a safe space for all of us and
if you had a misstep ku we all have
missteps but the groan you know adult
thing is to take accountability and say
yo my fault
well burr up give me a call I like to
I'm right I'm right here and put it on
social media cuz it was all over the
place so it's a time to be like I was
wrong I don't talk about light-skinned
jokes go because it's stupid and I'm not
stupid
I was in Grenada and I was I was totally
joking and I go like people can't be
revolutionaries I had to stop it before
you make a jump by not playing seals all
right well it's false yes
I don't think jokes are funny when
they're not true like this just the
reality like most jokes what makes them
most funny as they're true well your
friend hurts my feelings every day yep
calls me babe beige [ __ ] well can we
grow we're not beige mean we're sparkly
beige and now if there's one person who
reinforces every negative stereotype of
light-skinned men though it is
absolutely I mean you got emotional with
Jesus on some light-skinned [ __ ] like
you okay but now I'm sitting next to a
black [ __ ] charlemagne interview the
whole time because I know what he's
gonna be trying to keep the mood like my
guys know he wants somebody to fight
and that's what it should be that's what
should be and so you know but also like
I feel like when people say like oh you
know when you make a white people jokes
its divisive
I think that's [ __ ] I do think it is
divisive though when we amongst the
black community enforce and reinforce
color is amongst ourselves so like I
shouldn't be making dark-skinned jokes I
don't think there should be light
skinned jokes made I think you know at
the end of the day you definitely can't
do it Oscar I would never why would I
there's nothing funny but do Adolphe can
go back at them you can jump from a
different era see I understand it but I
just feel like there's just no there's
just no place at this point and then it
just gets out of hand and then start
people started you know being
disrespectful like that's what it goes
from being like light-hearted to like
we're disrespectful at the end of the
day we was all slaves
so let's hire these lights we lay is
like someone's in the field someone's in
the house getting raped and I'm the kind
of I'm the kind of mother where I feel
like I would have been in the house I
put me in the field I don't even want to
be here with y'all puppy anything I
you'd have been awesome that you'd have
been that Turner huh not what you media
break for a minute why was that I took a
social media break because I realized
that I had not adjusted how I was
interacting with social media even
though my social media had shifted like
I went from having 40,000 followers in
like June of 2017 to almost a million by
the end of the year or by the time I did
in this year so by March
and I was still operating the same way
where I'm like inter trying to interact
with everybody and then I'm clapping
back and doing all type of stuff and
it's just like this is not healthy this
is and and I also got like hemmed up in
a silo of Lies that got me a lot of
death threats and people attacking me in
all type of [ __ ] on the intro to my
whole trope and you know it's always a
continued narrative of like Amanda
Steele hates black men which is just so
tired and false and it's just like I'm
all like I'm only human I can only
withstand so much just watching lies
about myself be continuously purported
by people and also by women I think
that's really what annoys me the most
when you have women that like take time
out of their day to like come at me and
be like you lioness and I'm just like
but the facts is in front of your face
you just wanted to get at me so when you
slave always wanted to get at you and
they were waiting for an opportunity I
found one and they want to come from my
neck and I'm just like you know what in
the words of the whoo I will protect my
neck and I will go to Grenada and my my
business and end up doing you know a
beautiful photo shoot in Grenada that
you can now see in essence yeah and you
know that's always funny it's like on
the internet you find out that you just
really get to see in real time like
people taking time out of their lives to
hate you at the exact same time that
you're literally doing like your
favorite thing in the let me just say
let me just pay attention to it and the
problem is that people also don't listen
to things for themselves no they'll take
like a little clip somebody else saying
something and feed off of that and never
go listen to the actual what was said
was this and you can say it a million
times like no that's not what I said
but that's why I'm really trying to just
really reiterate and encourage folks
like you are smart enough to handle and
read things for yourself like you we we
have the people need to get back to
knowing that we have the resources
within ourselves to form our own
opinions and we don't realize how much
we have been led astray
the the amount of access to media and to
other people's opinions that we're no
longer forming our own we're literally
waiting for someone to form an opinion
for us people come on my DMS all the
time like I want to hear your thoughts
on this I want to hear your thoughts on
this and it's like what let me what are
your thoughts on this right like I want
to hear your thoughts if we're all gonna
have access to platforms we should be
actually being conscious of how we're
using our platforms and that's what
people don't understand if you have an
Instagram you might have four followers
you have a platform like I'll see people
who would be like oh well there that's
just a act that they do want Instagram
you know that's not really who they are
or like oh I'm just posting that for my
Instagram but that's not really what I
believe and I'm like what are we gonna
start actually admitting that the
Internet is now an extension of your
reality and if you are on there being
fake then you are big that's not it's
not it's nothing it's not virtual social
media is not virtual reality it is
actual reality it's an extension of
yourself if you on they're doing some
[ __ ] [ __ ] and that means you are doing
some [ __ ] [ __ ] not some other person who
exists in social media land so for me
I'm like yo you need to check yourself
Amanda and I took my I did my own self
check during that time like how how are
you adding to the things that you're
complaining about you know like with all
the clapping back and with all the
calling people out how could you be
better so that's when I shifted and
decided I need to be more about calling
people in versus calling them out I need
to be more conscious of how I speak
about things and try and be more
positive and that's just my life in
general trying to think more positively
about things and not just be so quick to
be like well let me tell ya you know but
sometimes you have to have those moments
but I try and do self check and I think
the internet doesn't let you do that
sometimes because everything needs to be
so and people love to bring up receipts
and it's like yes that is a receipt of
my past but I am now moving in a
different space in the future and I
should be allowed to do that
Amanda Steel's no she's an acquired
taste though I'm not for everybody
exactly you know that about you but I
think that's thrill self-awareness when
you realize like I'm not for everybody
like and nobody should be for everybody
because that's loose oh I know even has
the bandwidth to be for everybody my
whole thing is that if I'm not for you
chill that's it that's all I'm saying
like if I'm not for you you don't need
to come and get at me
I'm just not for you there's so many
other places for you to be then in my
timeline telling me you don't like me
and you gotta realize that people really
don't know you at the end of the day
they really don't and what's wild is
that so I could be on Instagram and have
all these dashes in my insta story and
it still only adds up to six minutes of
my day mm-hmm and people will judge you
off those six minutes and think that
like you spent your whole day ranting
it's like no actually I had sex like
three times today pass checks like I'm
hung out with my cat had a great day I
had a great day I did an entire show and
in the midst of that I talk some [ __ ]
and you watch me get my makeup done what
do you think black women being sidelined
the comedy is over or the landscape
changing oh it's not over I mean I'm one
wrong way to go and even I'm you know
still like you know a light-skinned
chick from a very specific point of view
so there's definitely a long way to go
and I think the reality though is that
it's my it's part of my it is part of my
responsibility to be an integral part of
opening that space so that's why I do
smart funny in black and you know create
spaces where we can give people bigger
platforms and bring them up on stage and
have them be guests that's why I have my
podcast small doses and we can have
folks come on and that's why I want to
have a festival it's my funny and black
festival you know we just we just did a
takeover at the Kennedy Center you dope
and I did three I headline three nights
at the Kennedy Center and I want to go
back next year and do the same thing but
during the day have programming that
gives you know space for other comics
that fall under the umbrella but yeah
patriarchy over even when we have the
meetings up here and people are like
okay who are you are the top comedians
they never say a woman's name we haven't
had a shot at the top mm-hmm we haven't
had a shot at the top of my three
favorite comics are Jerry Seinfeld Dave
Chappelle and Chris Rock and people are
like why don't you have a woman in there
I'm like when I was growing up there
wasn't a woman comedian at the forefront
for me to even be influenced by it like
performers feel like Tichina Arnold and
Tisha Campbell and you know Jasmine guy
like they were killing it increase
summer etc but on like some stand up
with it we're out here we're not getting
the platform yeah like some more I think
some more as Abby's and she's been out
here for everything everything yep you
know she's really funny I'm hilari
yeah yeah I go see I do go see more
women comments nowadays than I do guys
why I don't know
because you're going through a hall
awakening there was a lot I think a lot
of dudes are like women ain't funny
and it's like no you're not dating funny
women I mean that's it like I mean and a
lot of dudes can't handle dating a funny
woman they can't handle the barbs they
can't handle the jokes coming at them
you know and they're really feel away
like you got to be a certain kind of
brother to be able to like manage like
okay I may say some slick [ __ ] but
relationships cracking up do cracking on
each other yeah yeah I know why I go see
more women comments cuz a lot of male
comments have the same POV yes that's
what it is especially especially black
ones have the same POV on a lot of
things that's why I enjoy going to see
women comments and women comics who are
really doing their thing right now are
able to do their thing because they're
not just talking about sex you know like
it's not just a small topic space that
they're in no we have expanded beyond
that and so you get to hear just all
different voices and it's time it's time
but I'm telling you [ __ ] really think
that women aren't funny because they're
dating chicks that can't make jokes and
I'm like do you feel especially served
his purpose the purpose you intended it
to have yeah the special definitely
served its purpose because I still get
black women coming to me saying thank
you for the special I still get black
women saying like you know this has been
really special for me and gave me a
voice and it's still resonating like it
didn't die down like it's been six
months and I still get people like
sending me videos of them closing
windows and being like these are not
windows you know and and I think that's
that's exciting that that can happen I
mean like my him walked into his
godmothers crib and she was watching the
special he was like why are you watching
this and they were like we love her and
it's like wow
so you are tell us about him no is he an
industry I'm not doing this from the
East Coast West Coast yes oh she said
yesterday is he mama proof he met my mom
and my aunt you read the whole squad he
met your dad you got Brady good you
straight young Oh your age my age
anything else brother is he funny
hilarious yeah hilarious you know I
can't I mean I you know you have to be
smart you have to be smart funny black
to even get in the door with me where'd
you guys meet at a museum store you'll
see his back a lot right here I really
was out there was hugged up on the couch
the fact that he's traveling with you
playing early in the morning beautiful
that's great all right yeah she's gotta
go you had a man every morning yeah I'm
not that life okay how does he feel
about [ __ ] got me [ __ ] up
he was like baby that's a hit yeah there
you go that's all that matters like
that's a hit coz you know but at the end
of the day like you just want to be able
to have somebody that you can bounce
things off of and that listens to you
and you can listen to them and I will
say like all of this is a learning curve
like you just realize like that there's
just different paths to every
relationship and how things grow and you
know that you learn things about
yourself and about each other and
patience and all of that but you also
just I'm just older I'm older so I find
that I'm just having to just really look
at myself and my triggers oh that's
something that you learn about in an in
a new relationship like oh that's a
trigger I didn't even know hey you know
and so that's been but it's just nice to
be growing like to know that you're
growing and to know that you're evolving
and that someone is trying like that's
the thing I think a lot of a lot of
women get frustrated with the fact that
like they don't feel like someone is
willing to just try to like get over the
hump like cuz it's a huh you got to make
that effort it's not gonna be just if
you're listen I always say revolution a
revolutionary woman's love will not be
won passively hmm so like to me when
you're rocking with someone like me like
the easy doesn't come in the beginning
the easy comes on the other side like we
gonna go through the rapids and then
it's gonna be serene but it's because
like you're dealing with someone who is
an established human you know like I
have had to be me at the full extent of
me for my whole life to get to where I'm
going so that is not so that's not very
malleable yeah I mean like I'm not I'm
not you're working with granite not clay
okay so you got a chip away and I have
to be
to allow that to happen to and that has
to happen with the other person because
if you're like me you're gonna be with
somebody who is in the same boat I don't
want no [ __ ] I could just walk over and
you know I don't want no dude this is
gonna be like whatever you say you know
like I'm not trying to reenact coming to
America with me as like a dog nah you
know but you have to respect each other
and it's like sometimes that can be a
journey and also it's just the realities
of like where you're coming from like
we've all been through [ __ ] at this age
in our life we've all been through stuff
right and your baggage is real and it's
very hard to not put your baggage at the
door of your temple and have someone
crawl over it to get to you it can be
very difficult so at the end of the day
it's like okay well let's unpack this
all together and that takes time and
patience and dedication and you just
want a lot of women in my boat feel like
they can't find somebody who's willing
to do that with them they really do and
I get it and I mean you don't know how
long things are gonna last but it's at
least nice to see someone show effort
like to show the effort and show a will
of state to say like okay you in a space
over here and I'm gonna see what's up
with this space like I may not like and
I'm someone who's like yo [ __ ] may not
last forever but at least like someone
being willing to say let me at least try
like let me in a real way a lot of these
dudes that I've dated especially like
from LA and they look good on paper
they're so like you need to be there
show about them being the catch right
that they don't feel that they need to
adjust and I'm like well I know I'm the
catch and I'm willing to adjust so why
can't it be symbiotic there has to be
symbiosis and a lot of brothers don't
understand that the women that they
claim to want are not going to lay down
we're not in state property we're not
get down lay down like we are okay let's
both step up like I was soon as I look
up what's in biosis me calm down one
time I was like Nicki you need to calm
up because what I was saying was like
you're - you're being too chill about
this issue like I need you to elevate to
where I'm at right now about this issue
but with issue it's irrelevant but the
point is that the point is that we all
have to try and be our best selves and
sometimes in relationships like it's so
easy to regress it's so easy to just
like go back to our previous dysfunction
because it's comfortable and the [ __ ]
that's really difficult is like being
honest with yourself about like how am i
continuing my my how am i continuing my
practices that got me in the [ __ ]
before right you got to learn from your
past relationships and grow woo and
that's you know then you standing in the
mirror like Mary Jay with black lipstick
on so you know so man that's happy I am
good
I mean be happy when it's not good look
good but y'all cute okay I walked out
there play [ __ ] got me [ __ ] up her
man said this is a hit how would he know
is the hit is he a rapper or something
please lay the record you know you so
much this autumn again is a little ditty
on my Instagram after somebody has sent
me an unsolicited dick pic and then
tried to tell them the wrong number and
so what I did was I told my followers I
screen started it with his phone number
and I told my Instagram following like
hey I don't like to were following my
Instagram fam I say hey can you send
this dude pictures of birth so you can
ruin [ __ ] for him yes
and he sent and they sent him pictures
of like birth like babies popping from
vaginas to ruin vaginas for him and then
he texted me and was like you fell for
putting your people on me and you know
that I was this is a wrong number up
with a I sang it on my Instagram and
then chance posted it and you posted it
you still haven't posted my video and
you didn't tag me my fault my fault my
fault guard I will see I will take
accountability and that I so listen she
given a story but the story behind the
record and so the reality though is that
[ __ ] got me [ __ ] up is not just
about [ __ ] and I say this in my
standup like [ __ ] got me [ __ ] up
sometimes you say that you talking about
white people you talking about just
people in general who are acting
ignorant they got you [ __ ] up cuz they
got you thinking they got you [ __ ] up
because they're thinking that you being
classy or you being cool or you being
just you know an upstanding person is is
giving a door for them to play you know
it's not the case so let this be your
summer anthem y'all let's be happy and
jovial posted on days ago okay fair
enough
so anyway this is my summer anthem for
the real one sorry this is my summer
anthem for the real ones
[ __ ] got me [ __ ] yet alright well
thank you for joining us yeah and fields
got a book coming out - I do small doses
is the literary component to my podcast
it's coming out October 22nd I'm scared
out of my mind about that's double
booked but I got the book cover
yesterday and but thank y'all so much
for always giving me a space to come up
here please y'all let's make sure to
come out - smart funny and black that
you know the vibe onyx 101 tour we are
hitting the road all of july 2019 you
can go to smartphone you black comm to
get your tickets and the reality is that
we can't just wait to get tickets last
minute let me tell you about these shows
no listen I feel you these venues really
don't want us there no they don't they
don't want us there and the only thing
they care about is money that's the only
thing that talks and ticket sales and
what do you have to show them is that
ticket sales are happening early because
they don't expect for us to do numbers
so until we show them that we do numbers
they don't show us love and they're
still gonna be racist when we go to the
sometimes some of these venues they're
still gonna act funny but there's more
of us than them and so when I say more
of us I mean that there really are more
smart funny black Hispanic no take that
back not Hispanics smart funny black
latina ex homosexual trans Asian etc etc
etc people there's like all of us
there's so much more of us and there are
the ignorant and until we yes and until
we show our numbers they're gonna still
run [ __ ] so you cop tickets that's how
you show numbers and when you cop
tickets smart pony and black you're
supporting an independently owned and
created black woman's business all right
well thank you Amanda SEALs for joining
us thank you
having me as always is the Breakfast
Club as Amanda sales
[Music]